# Lawrence Ogbeifun

Résumé

PhD candidate in Economics at the University of Mississippi. My research interests lie in macroeconomics and span time series analysis, labor, monetary, and environmental economics. I am particularly interested in labor market reform in a dynamic and stochastic general equilibrium (DSGE) framework. I strive to answer questions in my research that are both academically interesting and policy relevant.

#### **EDUCATION**

2017–2023 University of Mississippi, Ph.D., Economics, Expected March 2023.

2017–2019 **University of Mississippi**, *M.A.*, Economics.

Summer 2020 **University of California (Virtual)**, *Berkeley/Sloan Summer School*, Environmental and Energy Economics.

2021 Tekedia Institute (Virtual), Mini-MBA.

Summer 2021 **Dynare (Virtual)**, Dynare Summer School.

2015–2016 University of Lagos, Nigeria, M.Sc., Economics.

2009–2012 University of Benin, Nigeria, B.Sc., Mathematics and Economics.

#### SKILLS

MATLAB Advanced Stata Advanced

R Advanced LATEX Advanced

\_ ....

Python Intermediate SQL Intermediate

Tableau Intermediate RATs Basic

Google Intermediate

MS-Office Advanced

Analytics

## EXPERIENCE

2021-present **Instructor**, *University of Mississippi*.

• Prepare and deliver lectures to undergraduate students on courses such as principles of macroeconomics and microeconomics.

E-views Advanced

- Develop instructional materials.
- Evaluate and grade students' class work, assignments, and papers.
- o Initiate, facilitate, and moderate classroom discussions.

2019–2022 **Teaching Assistant**, *University of Mississippi*.

- Undergraduate Level Experimental Economics
- Graduate Level Macroeconomics
- Graduate Level Econometrics

2017–2020 **Research Assistant**, *University of Mississippi*.

1/2 Lawrence Ogbeifun

- o Perform research and analyze all economic policies and issues.
- Analyze and prepare various economic data sets.
- o Prepare various charts and graphs for all economic data and draft relevant articles.
- o Coordinate with other colleagues to research on various economic issues and analyze all statistics.
- Develop original quantitative research projects.
- Summer 2020 **Teaching Fellow**, *Michigan State University*, America Economic Association Summer Program.
  - o Organized recitation lectures and assignments for classes
  - Guide class discussions.
  - Evaluate student work.

# HONORS AND AWARDS

- o Summer Research Assistantship, Graduate School, University of Mississippi, 2022.
- o The National Opinion Research Center, 2022.
- o Graduate Student Award, Southern Economic Association, Fall 2021.
- Graduate Assistantship, 2017–2023.

### SERVICE

- 2017–2018 Graduate Student Council Senator, University of Mississippi.
  - Representing economics graduate students.
- 2017–2018 Volunteer, University of Mississippi.
  - Green Grove Gameday Recycling Program.

2/2 Lawrence Ogbeifun